A Guide to the Papers of C. Alphonso Smith, 1900-1931
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of C. Alphonso Smith 1900-1931
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
924
This collection consists of 10,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited by C. Alphonso Smith on in July 1940.
Contents List
- Correspondence June 4, 1900 - December 1, 1905 (Box 1)
- Correspondence January, 1906 - March, 1907 (Box 2)
- Correspondence April, 1907 - June, 1909 (Box 3)
- Correspondence July, 1909 - January, 1911 (Box 4)
- Correspondence January, 1911 - December, 1911 (Box 5)
- Correspondence December, 1911 - October, 1912 (Box 6)
- Correspondence October, 1912 - May, 1913 (Box 7)
- Correspondence May, 1913 - January, 1914 (Box 8)
- Correspondence January, 1914 - September, 1914 (Box 9)
- Correspondence October, 1914 - May, 1915 (Box 10)
- Correspondence June, 1915 - January, 1916 (Box 11)
- Correspondence February, 1916 - July, 1916 (Box 12)
- Correspondence August, 1916 - February, 1917 (Box 13)
- Correspondence March, 1917 - March, 1918 (Box 14)
- Correspondence March, 1918 - December, 1918 (Box 15)
- Correspondence January, 1919 - October, 1919 (Box 16)
- Correspondence November, 1919 - May, 1920 (Box 17)
- Correspondence June, 1920 - April, 1921 (Box 18)
- Correspondence May, 1921 - October, 1921 (Box 19)
- Correspondence November, 1921 - October, 1922 (Box 20)
- Correspondence November, 1922 - February, 1923 (Box 21)
- Correspondence 1923 (Box 22)
- Correspondence 1923 (Box 23)
- Correspondence ca. 1923-1924 letters to Miss Fannie Smith (Box 24)
- Correspondence 1924 Corres. On Dr. Smith's death (Box 25)
- Correspondence ca. 1924 (Box 26)
- Correspondence 1924-1925 (Box 27)
- Correspondence July 1, 1925 - December, 1925 (Box 28)
- Correspondence 1926 (Box 29)
- Correspondence Christmas, 1926 - January, 1927 (Box 30)
- Correspondence April, 1927 - Correspondence re: Death of Miss Smith (Box 31)
- Correspondence April, 1927 - November, 1927 (Box 32)
- Correspondence 1927 (Box 33)
- Correspondence 1927 - 1929 (Box 34)
- Correspondence April, 1928 - September, 1928 (Box 35)
- Correspondence September, 1928 - February, 1928 (Box 36)
- Correspondence 1929 - 1930 (Box 37)
- Correspondence January 1, 1930 - [?] (Box 38)
- Correspondence 1920 - 1930 (Box 39)
- Correspondence 1931 (Box 40)
- Correspondence 1929 - January 1930 June, 1930 - January 3, 1931 (Box 41)
- Correspondence 1931 - Also E.A. Poe material (Box 42)
- Correspondence and Manuscripts of C.A. Smith, Jr. (Box 43)
- Clippings and letters (Box 44)
- Miscellaneous checks and bills (Box 45)
- Letters and Notes (Box 46)
- Letters and Notes (Box 47)
- Letters and Notes (Box 48)
- Letters and Essays (Box 49)
- Assorted curiosa from Berlin (Box 49)
- Essays, Letters, Berlin items (Box 50)
- Unsorted letters (Box 51)
- Lecture Notes, South. Lit. Letters (Box 52)
- Clippings, Essays, and Letters (Box 53)
  O. Henry (William Sidney Porter) Material
  ALS, Porter, New York, to Smith, 24 February 1908, published in the Bookman, August 1913, p. 601.
  Two pocket notebooks, ca. 1901, with brief notes on Porter's short story ideas and the magazines to which his manuscripts were sent, addresses of persons chiefly of New York and Boston, and a few miscellaneous notes and comments.
  ALS, Sarah Coleman Porter, Mountain Park Hotel, to Mr. and Mrs. Smith, December 18, 1907, mentioning Porter and a criticism of him.
  LS, Theodore Roosevelt, New York, to Smith, December 20, 1916, commenting on Smith's biography of Porter.
  Snapshot of Porter, endorsed "'O. Henry' from Mrs. Sara Coleman Porter June 5, 1910."
- Personal and Family Correspondence (Box 54)
- Miscellaneous Papers (Box 55)
- Private Papers # 1 (Box 56)
- Private Papers # 2 (Box 57)
- Unsorted Letters and Checks (Box 58)
- Miscellaneous Papers (Box 59)
- Reprints, Articles, Clippings (Box 60)
- Review of "What Can Literature Do For Me?" Keynote studies, Publisher's Letters (Box 61)
- Essays, Articles (Box 62)
- Naval Academy, Galleys of Poe and the Bible (Box 63)
- Reprints, Copies, etc., of Articles (No. mss.) Naval Academy (Box 64)
- Articles and Naval Academy (Box 65)
- North Carolina, and Naval Academy (Box 66)
- Miscellaneous Articles, Notebooks, Some German material (Box 67)
- Miscellaneous Papers and Articles (Box 68)
- Miscellaneous Newspapers and Magazines (Box 69)
- Magazines and Newspapers (Box 70)
- Newspapers (Box 71)